{
    "id": "178d9944820840b487e77fa2027bbf00",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "My father ............................... for a brisk walk every evening.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habits, routines etc.",
            "answers": [
                "is going",
                "goes",
                "has gone"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………………. for Singapore tomorrow.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about future events that are part of a timetable.",
            "answers": [
                "leave",
                "are leaving",
                "will leave"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. all of my problems.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about finished events when the focus is on completion. ",
            "answers": [
                "solved",
                "have solved",
                "had solved"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. to post the letter yesterday.",
            "description": "To simply say that something happened in the past, use the simple past. ",
            "answers": [
                "have forgotten",
                "forgot",
                "had forgotten"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………. his breakfast when I visited him.",
            "description": "The past continuous is used for the longer background action that was going on when another action took place. ",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "has",
                "was having"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………….. him before.",
            "description": "The present perfect is common with expressions like never, ever, etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "never saw",
                "have never seen",
                "had never seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… the problem with the minister last week.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have discussed",
                "discussed",
                "had discussed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ……………………….. the next day.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will come",
                "would come",
                "come"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The letter ……………………….. yesterday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "posted",
                "was posted",
                "had posted"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher ……………………….. the boy for misbehaving in the class.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "reprimanded",
                "reprimands",
                "had reprimanded"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you like this book, you ………………………. take it.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "could",
                "can",
                "will"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………… president.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "elected",
                "has elected",
                "was elected"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}